

Abhishek Pandey Data Engineer

PROFILE

Total 6+ years of experience in IT Industry involving Software Analysis, Design, Implementation, Coding,

Development, Reporting, Testing and Maintenance with focus on Data warehousing applications using ETL tools like Talend, Reporting Tools like Tableau and SQL for datalake operations.

STRENGTHS

- Excellent interpersonal, communication skills and ability to interact effectively with address concerns.
- Excellent prioritization, time management, analytical and Organizational skills.
- Always maintained healthy professional ambience with the customers and Team members.

CONTACT

abhipandey976@gmail.com +91-9769587673 Vikhroli, Mumbai

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ETL & BI Tools Talend Open Studio, Tableau Desktop, Tableau Prep, Informatica

Databases PostgresSQL, Greenplum

Programming PL/Sql, SQL

Other Tools Pgadmin, Github Desktop, DBeaver, Putty, MS-Office, Winscp.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services

Jan 2019 - Present

Data Engineer

Self Service (GE Power)

- Strong experience in business analytics workflow using Talend Real-Time Big Data Platform 7.3 and Visualization skills with Tableau 2020.2.
- Create ETLs using Talend Open Studio, SQL, to get the relevant data. This requires
 extensive transformation of data using SQL and SQL Functions.
- Experience and Knowledge working on Talend Administration Center(TAC).
- Organize Codes in **Git Repository** and Push and Pull from the repositories for migration.
- Create Data Models, Fact Tables and Dimension Tables to provide a representation to the end
 users and the clients.
- Create Tableau Data Sources and Dashboards from the ETL Tables and define the cosmetics based on the Hierarchy and Granularity of the data thereby using Folders, Connections and Schedules of the Data Sources
- Worked on Agile Methodologies using Rally.

Tata Consultancy Services

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Talend Developer

Aurora Migration

- Responsible for migration of 1400+ Complex Talend Jobs/database queries from Greenplum to PostgreSQL which involved creating, changing, optimizing, deploying the jobs on server, testing and maintaining data quality issues by ensuring the logical functionality is intact while converting the jobs/queries to their Aurora equivalent.
- Gained comprehensive knowledge of Talend Open Studio components and its features along
 with Talend Administration Center and worked on Ingestion, Outgestion and Master jobs
 between various databases and file systems like Oracle, MySQL, Greenplum and Excel files.

Tata Consultancy Services

Dec 2017 – Jan 2019

ETL/Informatica Developer

AWS AURORA MIGRATION

- Migration of 1200+ objects was done successfully, after resolving all the incompatibility issues and performance tuning.
- Performed requirement gathering with also provided valuable feedback and suggestions.
- This module was to refine and further process data (with several business logic) which is loaded in Data Lake From ETL Stage.
- All transformations/calculations are done here using SQL functions. The performance of various loads is also taken care of to meet the SLA.

EDUCATION

- B.S.C Information Technology, University of Mumbai (2014 2017)
- Degree Specialization :M.S.C Information Technology, University of Mumbai (2018 2020)

CERTIFICATIONS & AWARDS

- Recieved Best Team Award(2018), On the Spot Team Award(2021) and On the spot Award(2022)
- Appreciated by customers, stakeholders and leads for playing an important role in developing critical deliverable and providing post production deployment support for defects/changes raise.
- Completed The Complete sql bootcamp 2022 and Tableau Desktop Certification on Udemy Learning.